紅玫瑰白玫瑰 第一集
-==破爛熊樂園傾情奉獻==-
本字幕僅供學習交流，嚴禁用於商業用途
(本片含有部分性場面)
-=破爛熊字幕組=-
翻譯：tpring lovekeico
校對：lovekeico tpring
時間軸：馬老師的好學生
正體中文轉製及校對：Uriel
倫敦 1874年
London, 1874.
放機靈點
Keep your wits about you.
這座城市很大 錯綜複雜
This city is vast, and intricate,
你根本不知道這裏有什麼
and you do not know your way around.
想起從前讀過的故事 你可能覺得
You imagine, from other stories you've read,
你很瞭解這裏
that you know it well.
可它們故意迎合了你
But those stories flattered you.
你是個異類 從另一個時空陡然闖入
You are an alien from another time and place altogether.
你連現在幾點都不知道 對嗎?
You don't even know what hour it is, do you?
這裏大多數人也不知道
Nor do most where you're going.
他們的就寢時間依琴酒的酒力決定
Here people go to sleep as soon as the gin takes effect.
你會任憑自己被引入迷途
You've allowed yourself to be led astray
再也不用指望找到來路
and there's no hope of finding your way back.
伊麗莎白 我帶蠟燭來了
Elizabeth? I brought candles.
用不着 我沒什麼好看的
I won't need 'em. I'm not a pretty sight.
你看起來挺好      老天 蘇糖
You look all right.        Christ, Sugar.
你還會臉紅不會?
Don't you never blush?
怎麼回事?
What happened?
兩個人
Two of 'em.
不肯跟我回這邊
Wouldn't walk all the way back here.
「就在黑巷子裏野戰如何?」
"How about a quick soot-arse in the alley?"
他們一直狂笑
Never stopped laughing.
我會追到天涯海角 殺了他們      那還用説
I'm going to hunt them down and kill them.        Course you are.
你對欺負過你的人都是這樣
Like all the ones who ever done you mischief.
明天我就是一具臭皮囊了
Tomorrow I'll be cold meat.
他們會把我扔到河裏      他們不會的
They'll toss me in the river.        They won't.
我不讓他們這麼做
I won't let them.
鰻魚會啃光我的眼珠
Eels will eat out my eyes.
誰也不會記得有我這個人
No-one'll know I ever lived.
我記得
I'll know.
又是你 這回又來拯救誰來啦?
You again? Who have you come to rescue now?
我給伊麗莎白送牛蹄凍來的
I brought Elizabeth some calf's-foot jelly.
晚了
Too late.
她死了
She's dead.
飛 快飛 飛啊
Fly... Fly now...Fly!
是我帽子上的 她襲擊我 用...
It's from my hat. She struck at me with...
科魯? 去請科魯醫生了
Curlew? Doctor Curlew's been sent for.
親愛的福克斯太太 請這邊走
My dear Mrs Fox, please, this way.
是我該道歉纔對
It is we who must apologise.
宴會提前結束了
The party ended prematurely.
恐怕是我弟妹讓它戛然而止的
I'm afraid my sister-in-law brought it to a halt with a most
以最不幸的方式
unfortunate turn.
可憐的艾格尼絲
poor Agnes.
我想我還是...送您回家吧
I think it best for me to... see you home.
對不起 威廉
I'm sorry, William.
對不起 對不起 對不起
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
不用這樣
No need for that.
我還是你的小女孩嗎?
Am I still your little girl?
是
Yes...
你當然是
Of course you are!
永遠都是
Always.
別碰我      哦
Don't touch me.        No.
好 不碰你
No, of course not.
您知道 艾格尼絲很脆弱的
You know very well Agnes is delicate.
我們這麼窘迫 她壓力更大
Our current financial woes place an intolerable strain on her nerves.
難怪會發生這種小事故...
It's hardly surprising that little incidents like this...
小事故?
Little incidents?!
她用壁爐釬子敲掉了一個女士的帽子
She knocked a woman's hat clean off her head with a poker!
要是把人家眼睛戳了呢
She could have had her eye out!
她説她突然覺得憋悶
She felt trapped, she said.
然後就一眼看到
Next thing she caught sight of
布利德樓夫人帽子上的小鳥標本
the stuffed bird on Lady Bridgelow's bonnet
以爲它要展翅飛走
and believed it was about to take wing.
她只想幫它掙脱羅網
She sought only to free it from its yards of net.
你聽聽這都什麼話?
Can you hear yourself?
當然 這種衝動不對
An erroneous impulse, certainly...
不過精神可嘉吧
..but a generous one at least,
再説我們的經濟狀況這麼...
and given our current financial circumstances...
你要是眞想改善改善
If you want your circumstances to change,
該怎麼做你心裏有數
you know what you have to do.
心思放到生意上來
Turn your mind to the business!
今年的賬本我都給你一個月了
I gave you this year's accounts a month ago,
你看過沒? 一眼都沒有      我試過了
have you looked at them? No!        I have tried!
我天生就不是生意人
I do not have a flair for business!
我不像您
I am not like you!
我是個作家
I'm a writer!
你有作品嗎?
What have you written?
一本小冊子
A small pamphlet.
還沒出版
Not yet published.
老天爺
Dear God.
父親 只要您賣掉拉克漢香水廠...      賣掉?
Father, if you were only to sell Rackham's        Sell?
投資到這邊來
..and invest the proceeds,
賺的錢會讓我們都衣食無憂的
we could all live quite comfortably off the interest!
你的年金還得減
Your allowance was somewhat reduced.
你就當它全取消了吧
You may now consider it altogether withdrawn.
去吧 隨你幹什麼
You go ahead, you be your own man.
自己養活自己吧
At your own expense!
可是 父親      吃你的筆桿子去吧
But, sir        Write your way out of that!
父親...父親?
Sir...Sir?
怎麼就不勞那酒商大駕親自送來呢?
Why, pray, was the vintner unable to make this delivery in person?
憑什麼我
How did it come to pass
還要派你去取酒呢 克里斯托弗?
that I had to ask you to collect the claret, Christopher?
他説「告訴卡特韋夫人 因爲聖誕節到啦」
He says, "Tell Mrs Castaway it's cos of Christmas."
聖誕節
Christmas!
什麼叫聖誕節呀?
What is Christmas?
就是耶穌出生的日子
It's the day Jesus was born.
耶穌是誰?      他爲贖我們的罪而死
Who's Jesus?        He died for our sins.
看來是白費了 我們這不還贖着嘛
Evidently unsuccessfully, since we're all still paying.
男人噴出一股黏液
One squirt of slime from the man,
女人一顆腥臭的卵子
one fishy egg in the woman,
瞧呀
and behold -
他們就稱他...以馬內利 (耶穌的別名)
they shall call his name...Emmanuel.
給你帶熊油了
Got some bear's grease for ya.
謝謝 克里斯托弗
Thank you, Christopher.
就你自己? 沒帶位先生?
All alone, is it? No gent in tow?
伊麗莎白死了
Elizabeth is dead.
享清福去嘍
Gone to a better place.
她總説她要去好地方 對吧?
Always said she would, didn't she?
下一個是誰?
Who's next?
你?
You?
我?
Me?
記得今後胸衣裏帶把刀子
Be sure and carry a knife in your bodice from now on.
我肯定想不到用它的
I'd never have the wit to use it.
當心裙子
Watch your dress.
可別弄髒了
You don't want to spoil it.
爲這穿不了五分鐘的衣服 費的工夫可不小
A lot of trouble you go to for clothes that only stay on five minutes.
打擾一下 女士們
Excuse me, ladies.
我能有幸永遠留存你們的倩影嗎?
I would be honoured to preserve your image for all time!
永遠留存?
For all time?
不用了 謝謝      試試也無妨啊
No, thank you.        Go on. Why not?
我可不想千秋萬世
I'd rather not spend an indefinite future
被陌生人傳來傳去
being passed from hand to hand by strangers.
我倒不介意永遠被人記住
Wouldn't have minded being remembered for eternity, that's all.
伊麗莎白請我把她寫進我的書裏
Elizabeth asked me to put her in my book.
大概她也是這麼想的
Thinking the same, I suppose.
我原來最喜歡聽你讀你的書
I used to love it when you read your book to us.
可是我覺得...
But I wondered...
你有沒有想過寫點喜慶事進去呢
whether you ever thought of putting a bit of good fortune in.
比如從天而降的救星
Like a miraculous rescue!
沒有
No.
這是本仇恨的書 卡迪
It's a book of hate, Caddie,
用來報復每個外強中乾的
to wreak revenge on every pompous trembling worm
爬上卡特韋夫人門檻的小爬蟲
who taps at Mrs Castaway's door!
比爾
BILL!
波德利，阿什韋
Bodley, Ashwell.
你頭髮遭什麼殃啦?
What HAS happened to your hair?
啊 這個...是照馬修·阿諾德 (19世紀英國詩人 評論家) 剪的
Ah, it... It was supposed to look like Matthew Arnold.
剪得不像我挺高興的
I'm actually pleased it doesn't,
我覺得他的新作有點被吹捧過頭了
I...I think his latest work to be overrated.
來吧 老夥計 去喝一杯
Come on, old chap, let's get you a drink.
我們爲鑽研這本書可絞盡了腦汁了
So, we're quite worn out by the research for this book.
那你們想出名字了嗎?
And, do you have a title yet?
「禱告的效力」
The Efficacy of Prayer.
反諷的      對
It's ironic.        Yes.
有希望找到一家出版商嗎?
Is there any hope of finding a publisher for such a piece?
這年頭 總有雷霆般的呼聲在要求
There's a thundering call these days for books
那種打破社會結構的書 説到這個...
that destroy the fabric of society. Speaking of which...
你那部大作如何了?
how goes the great work?
按部就班的推進中
At its own pace.
好吧
Well...
也別全撲在書上
don't let the book consume you entirely.
近來你都成了隱士了 大好機會都喪失了
You're a virtual recluse these days, and such opportunities lost!
機會?
Opportunities?
露西·菲茨羅伊 纔14歳      哦
Lucy Fitzroy. Only 14.        Oh!
在喬吉娜夫人手下 使得一手好鞭子
Wields a vicious whip at Madame Georgina's.
好個小騷貨
An absolute fizgig!
不過我們眞正朝思暮想的是蘇糖
But the one we're just dying to have a crack at is Sugar.
蘇糖?      卡特韋夫人家的
Sugar?        Over at Mrs Castaway's,
那可是高級去處
a very high-class house.
當然 怎麼也吃不到口
Of course, one can never get her.
我都開始懷疑有沒有她這個人了
I begin to wonder if she even exists.
聲名遠播 十分誘人
The most intriguing reputation.
傳説她從不讓人失望
They say she never disappoints.
這總讓你文思泉涌了吧
That'd put ink in your nib, now.
門鈴這東西就不該讓人按兩次
It should never be necessary to ring a doorbell more than once...
...尤其是在...自己家裏
..especially if it is... one's own...
萊蒂
Letty.
拉克漢夫人還好嗎?      還好 先生
How is Mrs Rackham?        Well, sir, I believe.
科魯醫生和她在一起
Doctor Curlew is with her.
拉克漢先生?
Mr Rackham?
家裏沒有煤了
We're short on coal.
一直沒人送來
The delivery never arrived.
我換了一家煤鋪
I've changed supplier.
原來那家越來越靠不住了
Our fellow was becoming quite erratic.
(里德煤鐵公司 賬單 共15鎊)
(科魯醫生 賬單 10鎊)
拉克漢先生?
Mr Rackham?
科魯
Curlew.
請坐吧
Please.
眼下 她還挺清醒的
Well, she's tolerably lucid,
可我預料她很快就會崩潰
but I expect a full collapse very shortly.
是嗎?
Really?
我還覺得她好轉了呢
I had been thinking she seemed rather better.
那你就上當了
Then you're deluded.
拉克漢 每次我拜訪她
Rackham, every time I visit her,
她都要費很大自制力鎭定下來
she has to fight that much more strenuously to compose herself.
她對您的來訪壓力很大
She finds your visits very stressful.
也許我...      我很理解
Perhaps I...        I do understand
讓艾格尼絲暫時入院...
that having Agnes temporarily committed...
入院
Committed!
會使您痛苦 以及名譽受損
..would cause you personal pain and social embarrassment.
可我也見過別的人糾結於這個決定
But I have seen other men wrestle with the same decision and,
相信我 他們一旦下定了決心
believe me, once they have made it,
個個都如釋重負
they are relieved beyond words.
「聲名遠播 十分誘人」
'The most intriguing reputation.
「傳説她從不讓人失望」
'They say she never disappoints.
「卡特韋太太皇冠上的明珠」
'The jewel in Castaway's crown.
(紅髮女郎 蘇糖小姐)
「蘇糖」
'Sugar.
「價廉如棉布 享受如綾羅」
'Pay for cotton, but lie in silk.
「去乞討 去借 去偸 來買我春宵一度」
'Beg, borrow or steal to buy my services.
「來爐邊客棧找我」
'Seek me out at the Fireside Inn.'
我看起來怎樣 克拉拉?
How do I look, Clara?
眞美
Beautiful.
醫生説...我不能再讀書了
The doctor... says I'm not to read any more.
他説那...會刺激我
He...he says it excites me.
他也不是什麼都懂      對
Well, he doesn't know everything.        No.
(救命)
help
你眞是個淘氣的孩子!
You've been a very naughty boy!
你還沒告訴我們你是幹什麼的呢
So, you never told us what it is you do,
做什麼生意的?      生意
what line of business?        Business?
這個詞我提都懶得提
There's a word I've no time for!
不 我是個作家
No, I am a writer,
小説家 評論家
novelist, critic.
你叫什麼?      沒準我聽過你呢
What's your name?        I might've heard of you.
我估計不會
I very much doubt that.
你們幾位女士 恕我直言 不像讀書人
You ladies don't, if you'll excuse me, look like readers.
別看不起人了
I know more than you might expect.
我可試過狄更斯的      他早掛了吧?
I've had Charles Dickens.        Ain't he dead?
她舔的那部分還立着呢
Not the bit she sucked on!
那是誰?
Who's that?
那不是你在等的人嗎?
Is that who you're waiting for?
他和這裏一半傻瓜都在等
Him and half the fools in 'ere.
嘿 蘇糖      他説他是作家
Hey, Sugar!        Writer, he says!
在等你呢
Waiting for ya.
八成等了一輩子了吧
All his life, I don't doubt!
晚上好 您是...
Good evening, Mr...
亨特
Hunt.
有個H的
With an aitch.
呃 喬治·亨特
Er, George Hunt.
你是...
And you are...?
蘇糖就是我的姓名 亨特先生
Sugar is all there is to my name, Mr Hunt.
蘇糖
Sugar.
希望您沒有等很久 和這三女巫
I do hope you haven't been waiting too long with the Three Witches
在一起
for company.
三女巫...這是馬克白裏的
The Three Witc... That's Macbeth.
請原諒我的儀容
You must forgive my appearance.
這惡劣天氣把我的頭髮全給糟蹋了
This foul weather plays havoc with my hair.
我的也是
Oh, mine too!
我專門照着馬修·阿諾德剪的
I had it cut. It was supposed to look like Matthew Arnold.
剪得不像      慶幸吧
It doesn't.        Be thankful.
我覺得他有點被吹捧過頭了
I think he's rather overrated,
不過您當然比我明智
but I'm sure you know much better than I.
不 我同意
No! I agree.
那還用説
Absolutely.
怎麼也比不上拉斯金 (19世紀英國藝術評論家)
Give me Ruskin, any day!
如果您説的是拉斯金先生的散文
If it is Mr Ruskin's prose you're referring to,
那我完全同意
then I quite concur.
他的詩就免了
Spare me his poetry.
他的韻律確實乏善可陳
In verse he's a major minor.
丁尼生的新作 多麼奇妙
Tennyson's latest work, pure whimsy.
多麼奇妙 簡直...異想天開
It's whimsy, it's whi...whimsical.
有個詩人 詹姆斯·湯普森(18世紀蘇格蘭詩人)
It's... There is a poet, James Thompson.
詹姆斯·湯普森?
James Thompson?
對 詹姆斯·湯普森 他最新的作品
Yes, James Thompson, who in his latest work
眞是...翻天覆地
is truly...breaking new ground.
「闇夜之城」?
The City of Dreadful Night?
你知道?
You know it?
「世事輪轉 如同磨坊」
The world rolls round for ever like a mill.
「磨出善與惡 生與死」
It grinds out life and death and good and ill.
「沒有目標 沒有心靈 沒有頭腦」
It has no purpose, heart, nor mind,
「也沒有方向」
nor will.
年輕美麗的小姐不該記住這麼黑暗的意象
These are dark notions for a beautiful young woman to take to heart.
我的人生有時就這麼黑暗
My life can be dark sometimes.
人生得一知己
Kindred spirits, like yourself,
一世難求啊
are difficult to find.
你的嘴脣好像羽毛
Your lips are like feathers.
要它們帶你飛翔嗎?
Shall they help you take flight?
歡迎光臨卡特韋太太家 先生
Welcome to Mrs Castaway's, sir!
開一夜房 要五先令
The use of the room will cost you five shillings.
再加兩先令 還有美酒等着您
There can be good wine waiting for an additional two
可是上面發生什麼 要多久
but what happens up there, and for how long,
就由您和蘇糖自便了
is for you and Sugar to put a value to.
這是十先令
Here's ten shillings.
給我送酒上去
Send up some wine.
你累了 亨特先生
You're tired, Mr Hunt.
我很久沒好好睡覺了
I haven't been sleeping.
夜裏躺在牀上...
I go to bed at night...
也是通宵醒着
..and just lie awake.
好吧 我們來好好照顧你
Well...we shall have to take good care of you.
爐邊客棧的烈性麥酒
Strong ale at the Fireside.
「他從無夢的宿醉中醒來...」
'He woke from his dreamless drunkard's sleep...
「只見她正要割開他喉嚨」
'and found her poised to cut his throat.'
早安 亨特先生
Good morning, Mr Hunt.
早安?
Morning?
我睡了這麼久?      你很累了
I've slept so long?        Well, you were very tired.
還眞有點累 現在大概是...
Yes, I was. I believe it's...
蘇糖小姐 我似乎非常可惜 非常可恥地
Miss Sugar, I have suffered a most regrettable, most shameful
失禁了
loss of control.
濕衣服脱掉 亨特先生 馬上
Throw off your wet things, Mr Hunt. At once.
這眞是太過份了...
That is quite beyond...
我不指望你...        衣服拿來 謝謝
I can't expect you...        Your things, please, now.
這眞是...
This really is...
躺下吧
Lie back, now.
一切都會好的
All will soon be set to rights.
小可憐
Poor baby.
我太浪費你的時間了
I have taken up an unconscionable amount of your time.
完全沒有
Not at all.
你眞是個有趣的男人 喬治·亨特
You are a very interesting man, George Hunt.
我應該看看你的書
I shall look out for your books.
蘇糖小姐...
Miss Sugar...
沒有小姐 就叫蘇糖
No Miss. Just Sugar.
我的名字並不是...
My name is not, erm...
叫我威廉吧
Please just call me William.
原諒我的謊言 對男士來説聲譽很重要
Forgive the deception, but a man has a reputation to uphold.
姓名又有什麼意義呢?      是啊
And what's in a name?        Indeed!
這句話來自...       「羅密歐與茱麗葉」
That's actually a line from...        Romeo And Juliet.
再説...也許你很難見到我出版的作品
Also...you may struggle to find my work in published form.
寫作並不是我唯一的職業
Writing is not my sole occupation.
當然
Well, of course.
像你這樣擁有抑制不住的好奇心
Why would a man with your unquenchable curiosity,
博學多才 熟知世上種種奇蹟的男人
your Renaissance grasp of the world and its wonders,
怎麼會侷限在一個職業之中呢?
limit himself to just one sphere?
你當然會以這獨特而執着的心靈
Surely you would bring the same originality of mind
以不變應萬變吧?
and fixity of purpose to anything you were about?
藝術家手中 一切皆可爲藝術
All turns to art in the artist's hand.
福克斯太太
Mrs Fox,
我必須爲上次的事再次道歉
I must apologise again for our last encounter.
那時我和弟弟正處在最尶尬的處境
You found my brother and I at our absolute worst.
不會吧
Oh, I doubt that.
也許我該向你道歉
And I perhaps owe you an apology.
我那晚太心不在焉了
I was much preoccupied that night.
你的剋制只顯得禮數周全
I put your reserve down to good manners.
我下午去了一家妓院
I had that afternoon visited a bawdy-house
探訪一個快離開人世的女孩
to see a girl plainly not long for this world.
老天...      這很常見 有人專做病美人生意
Good L...        That's not uncommon, there's a trade in sick girls.
我向老鴇抗議過
I once complained to a madam
一個女孩甚至都站不穩了
that one of her employees could barely stand.
她告訴我這不需要站着
She told me standing was not mandatory,
還説我看起來也很憔悴
that I looked a bit peaky myself,
要不要找個房間躺下休息
and would I like to lie down in the spare room.
眞是狡猾又放肆的建議
A most sly and licentious suggestion.
你看我像生病了嗎?
Do I look ill to you?
完全沒有
Not at all.
好多了 萊蒂 眞的好多了
Better, Letty, much better.
除了把自己再弄乾淨點兒
Though you might tidy yourself up a little.
以不變應萬變
Fixity of purpose.
我一定要治好病
I am going to get well.
就算會被折磨死
Even if it kills me.
最親愛的艾格尼絲
Agnes, dearest.
他們使出看家本領了
They've really pushed the boat out.
希望你有個好食慾
I hope you have an appetite.
今天你能下來 眞是個愉快的巧合
What a happy coincidence it is that you've come down today.
巧合？       我制定了新的準則
Coincidence?        I am ushering in a new regime.
還給僕人們做了評估
Including a review of the staff.
家裏都亂成一團了
The household is out of hand.
並不只是今天
And it's not just today,
我是説 下雨天讓僕人們都手忙腳亂
I mean the rain makes the servants skittish, of course.
我經常觀察到這件事
I've observed this so often,
可以寫篇文章投給「笨拙」(19世紀倫敦幽默諷刺雜誌)
I mean to write a short piece for Punch on the topic.
問題是 僕人們需要女主人的領導
The fact is, servants look to their mistress for guidance,
接着管理他們對你也有好處 親愛的
and a return to overseeing them might be good for you, dear.
他們不能...自己處理嗎?
Can't...can't they just sort it out among themselves?
你不是常這樣説嗎?
I mean, isn't that what you always used to talk about?
社會主義?
Socialism?
社會主義不等於僕人失控
There is a difference between socialism and the staff running amok.
不知亨利忙完教堂的事會來嗎 我喜歡他 你呢?
I wonder if Henry will come after church? I like him, don't you?
最近的星期天 亨利都和福克斯太太在一起
Henry lately seems to spend his Sundays in the company of Mrs Fox.
科魯醫生的妹妹 那個寡婦? 你不是説...
Dr Curlew's sister, the widow? You don't mean...
不是
No!
上帝 不是
God, no!
福克斯太太只在乎她深愛的救濟社
And Mrs Fox is far too preoccupied with her beloved Rescue Society.
福克斯太太解救別人?
Mrs Fox rescues people?
妓女 親愛的
Prostitutes, dear.
我會告訴你 這無濟於事
A pointless crusade, if you ask me.
她不明白 大多數這種女孩
It doesn't seem to have occurred to her that many of these girls
都享受她們的工作
enjoy their work.
你還好吧 艾格尼絲?
Are you quite all right, Agnes?
要不要...
Would you like...
克拉拉
Clara!
萊蒂 珍妮       拉克漢太太?
Letty, Janey!        Mrs Rackham?
拉克漢太太
Mrs Rackham.
克拉拉 馬上去叫科魯醫生
Clara, send for Dr Curlew at once.
不要       不 拉克漢先生
No, no.        No, Mr Rackham.
照我説的做
Do as I ask!
藝術家手中 一切皆可爲藝術
All turn to art in an artist's hands.
你這麼突然就改變主意了?
All very sudden, this change of heart?
上天的指示和安排 父親
A revelation of Damascan proportions, sir.
我煥然一新了
I am a new man.
我還以爲你要歡樂的跑進來 把鉅額支票拍在我桌上
And I'm expected to jig for joy and slap a fat cheque on the desk,
是這樣嗎?        不是 我要證明自己 父親
is that it?        No, I wish to prove myself, father.
可以嗎?
If I may?
我帶來了我
I have brought my...
我對拉克漢家族賬目 不可抑制的好奇心
..unquenchable curiosity to bear on the Rackham accounts.
啊 威廉
Why, William.
能這麼快再見到你 眞好
What a pleasure to see you again, and so soon.
我給你帶了東西       眞的?
I brought you something.        Really?
上次忘記給你的
Something I forgot to give you last time.
你要寵壞我了
You spoil me.
亨特先生
Mr Hunt!
亨特先生 噢 亨特先生
Mr Hunt! Oh, Mr Hunt!
亨特先生
Mr Hunt!
我叫威廉·拉克漢
My name is William Rackham!
沒想到我還能見到這一天
I never thought I'd see the day.
你來遲了 蘇糖從來不等別人
You're too late. Sugar don't wait for no-one.
考慮一下吧?
Will you consider it?
我對蘇糖的專屬佔有權
Exclusive patronage of Sugar by me.
不
No.
爲什麼?       問題很複雜
What?        These matters are complex.
我們這是家小買賣
We have a small house here.
如果三分之一的服務都提供不了
If a third of what we offer is unavailable,
那我們怎麼辦?
where does that leave us?
還有其它的問題
Then there are other complications.
比如説?       我們和爐邊客棧的關係
Such as?        Our bond of mutual regard with The Fireside.
你這麼仰慕蘇糖的才色 當然也
Surely you, who are so appreciative of Sugar's merits,
看的出她是那裏的王牌
can see she is a draw there.
這只是細節
These are details.
我只有一個原則
It's the principle of the matter that I'm concerned with.
原則?
The principle?
蘇糖她自己是否同意?
Whether Sugar herself would agree?
能讓她下來嗎?
Might she come down?
畢竟 這是她自己的未來
It is her future at stake, after all.
還有一個方面你沒考慮到
There is another thing you haven't allowed for.
萬一要是蘇糖本人喜歡
You don't consider the possibility that Sugar might prefer -
恕我直言 喜歡多樣化呢?
forgive me - she might prefer variety?
好吧 讓她自己決定
Well, we shall let her decide.
亨特先生 見到你眞高興
Why, Mr Hunt, what a pleasure.
亨特先生
Mr Hunt...
有個提議給你 蘇糖
has a proposition for you, Sugar.
我聽説了
So I understand.
我想問一句
If I may.
我們都不明白的是
What none of us understands is,
除了給妓院方面的價錢...
outside of your arrangement with the house itself...
你還可以給蘇糖什麼?
..what will you pay Sugar?
我會不惜一切讓她開心
I will pay her whatever makes her happy.
好的 亨特先生...
Well, Mr Hunt...
我願意
I am willing.
幾點了?
What time is it?
你不用再辛苦工作了
You don't need to take in copy work any more,
不需要把自己搞的如此不堪了
or whatever it is you do to get yourself in such a mess!
拉克漢的産品裏有專門針對乾性皮膚的
You know, Rackham's does manufacture a product for dry skin.
可我已經是阿特金熊油的奴隸了
But I'm a slave to Atkinson's Bear's Grease.
你的人生從今以後就不同了
Your life is going to be very different from now on.
希望有些東西還是一樣
I hope some things remain the same.
（必須要出去）
must get out
（必須要多出去）
Must get out more
你的僕人安息日都在工作?
Your men work on the Sabbath?
像我一樣 一天都不夠用 亨利
As do I! Not enough hours in the day, Henry.
你知道香水也分八個調性
Did you know that there's an octave in perfume
像音樂那樣嗎?
as there is in music?
好吧 需要幫忙嗎?
Anyway, how can I help?
你有想到過媽媽嗎?
Do you ever think of mother?
沒有
No.
你很小時她就...去世了
You were very young when she, erm...passed on.
亨利 她和別的男人跑了
Henry, she ran off with another man.
抛棄了我們
She abandoned us.
我有時覺得 我們成長中
I am conscious, sometimes, that we lacked
環境裏缺乏...
growing up any, erm...
女性的陪伴
Female society.
你也知道吧 福克斯太太一直致力於幫助...
You know, of course, of Mrs Fox's efforts in the, erm...
社會的黑暗底層人士?
in the darkest recesses of the city?
我想她的行動支援
Well, I thought that her practical support
也許還需要我的...理論化的支持
might be well-supplemented by my more, doctrinal approach.
可我的問題是...
My problem, though, is this -
如果我想去關照
if I am to minister to, erm...
失足婦女...
..fallen women...
怎麼纔能辨認出她們呢?
..how shall I recognise them?
你好點了嗎?       熊油的效果很棒
Yer 'ands any better?        This bear's grease is miraculous.
你的書怎麼樣了?
How's yer book?
你知道我自學的識字
You know, I taught myself to read.
我可以教你
I could teach you.
不需要
Don't need it.
(拉克漢香水公司)
注意身後
watch your back!
只要一先令 我的手就屬於你 其它部分兩先令
My hand is yours for a shillin', sir, and any other part for two.
請把衣服穿好
Please, cover yourself up.
身體髮膚不是拿來買賣的
Your body parts are not yours to sell.
他們相互依存 全部屬於上帝
They belong together, and the whole belongs to God.
我的週身都屬於給的起兩先令的人 先生
My 'ole belongs to anyone that's got two shillings, sir.
聽我説
Listen to me.
我要你把這兩先令當成
I want you to see these two shillings as an act
不需再履行的行爲
that's no longer necessary.
它代替了...可以説是
It's in lieu, which is to say,
任何你打算做的事
whatever you were about to do,
求你 別這樣了
please, I beg you, don't.
「求你了 他請求着 拽着他的絲質領結」
"Please," he begged, tugging at the silken bonds.
「讓我走 我是個大人物」
"Let me go. I am an important man!"
「那就告訴我 高貴的紳士」
"So tell me, exalted sir,
「願意我的匕首從你身體哪部分刺進去?」
"where is it your pleasure to have this blade enter you?"
先生
Sir.
你遲到了
You're late.
工作太辛苦吧 拉克漢先生?
Hard at work, Mr Rackham?
我給你帶了東西
And I brought you something.
我幾個朋友出版的
A couple of my friends produced it,
它叫做「禱告的效力」
it's called The Efficacy of Prayer.
「波德利與阿什韋」
"Bodley and Ashwell."
眞是幼稚
How perfectly childish.
他們是不是沒事可做了?
Have they nothing better to do?
沒事可做
No, nothing
而你卻...       在這裏
Whereas you...        Exactly!
生意如何?       棒極了
How is the business?        Splendid.
你的敵人呢?
And your rivals?
競爭對手強硬麼?
Is the competition stiff?
皮爾斯和亞德里非常頑強
Well, Pears and Yardley are unassailable.
羅蘭和芮謎身體很好
Rowland and Rimmel are in good health.
尼斯本生病了 也許是致命疾病
Nisbett is ailing, perhaps fatally.
對不起 是不是很無聊?
I'm sorry, is this terribly dull?
一直講生意上的事?       無聊?
All this talk of business?        Dull?
還有誰比我
Who understands better than I
更懂藝術和商業的聯繫?
the connection between commerce and art?
我在想拉克漢産品的目錄
On which subject, I've been thinking about this Rackham's catalogue.
熏衣草潤足霜
"Lavender foot balm.
「腳臭是你的阿喀琉斯之踵嗎?」
"Are malodorous feet your Achilles' heel?"
我知道
I know, I know.
這是很早以前的
It was written years ago.
爸爸寫的 一點也不優雅
Father's work. Hardly elegant.
爲什麼不重寫?
So why not rewrite it?
還太早了
It's early days.
父親應該還沒準備好
I'm not sure Father's ready.
該是你帶頭的時刻了 而不是隨波逐流
It's time for you to lead, not follow.
讓我們的生意配的上拉克漢的名號
Let's make the business worthy of the Rackham name.
是威廉·拉克漢
William Rackham, that is.
沒有你我該怎麼辦
What would I do without you?
(地址 切普斯托路)
拉克漢太太
Mrs Rackham?
你醒了
you're awake.
是的 我想今天在樓下吃飯 克拉拉
Yes. I mean to take breakfast downstairs this morning, Clara.
您記得拉克漢先生今天不在嗎?
Have you remembered that Mr Rackham is away?
他去了丹地
He has gone to Dundee.
所以您要一個人吃早餐嗎?
So you'll take breakfast alone?
我覺得這樣更輕鬆
I think I shall find it easier that way.
我今早感覺特別精神 克拉拉
I feel so light this morning, Clara,
眞是無法描述的輕鬆
I can't tell you what a relief it is!
早餐後 我要做我的裙子了
After breakfast, I shall work on my dresses.
畢竟 社交季快到了
The season is almost upon us, after all.
可以把它拿過來嗎?
Would you bring them for me?
克拉拉 因爲...
Clara, with, erm...
因爲社交季快到了 一定...
..with the season so close, there are certain, er...
我還需要複習其他的技藝 比如...
skills I will need to re-master, such as, erm...
走出去...
..going outside, and, erm...
不需要人陪着 去散步
walking unsupported.
我想一會兒可以試試
I was, I was thinking we might try later.
如果您吃的消的話
If you feel up to it.
也許等科魯醫生在的時候?
Perhaps after Dr Curlew's been round?
可他一定...
But surely...
今天他一定不會來吧?
Surely he isn't coming today?
不 我...
No, I'm...
我不要見他 克拉拉
I won't see him, Clara.
就是不要
I simply won't.
切普斯托路
Chepstow Villas.
勞駕你遠道而來
I'm sorry you have come all this way
不巧的是對你來説 我非常好
because, unfortunately, for you, I am quite well.
我看你很蒼白
You're looking very pale to me.
也許是因爲臉上撲的粉吧?
That may be the face powder, mayn't it?
我不是告訴你不要用化粧品嗎?
Have I not cautioned you against the use of cosmetics?
你不是説你已經扔...
And did you not tell me that you had disp...
扔掉了 對 所以肯定不是
Disposed of it, yes. So I did. So it cannot be that.
可是我太累 不想檢査了
But I am too tired to be examined.
你的疲倦或許是疾病的症狀
Your tiredness may in itself be a symptom of illness.
你每週都給我做檢査
You examine me every week.
一次不做又會怎樣?
What harm can it do to leave it undone just this once?
只有瘋女人纔願意讓自己惡化下去
Only a madwoman would willingly let her health decline...
我不是瘋女人       所以我纔開口請求
I am not a madwoman!        Which is why I ask permission,
而不是像對瘋人院的病人一樣強迫
rather than obliging you as I would an asylum inmate.
克拉拉
Clara?
我要留下嗎?
Should I stay?
不用
No.
疼痛是抗拒引起的
The pain lies entirely in the resistance.
放鬆
Little more.
再放鬆
好的
Good.
謝謝
Thank you.
這條裙子很難修補了 你覺得呢?
The dresses will be hard to mend, don't you think?
不可能補好了
I don't think we can mend them.
我做夢了 克拉拉
I dream, you know, Clara.
夢?
Dream?
夢到一個地方 不是...
Of a place. Not...
一個不是眞實存在的地方
Not a place with a physical dimension, but one that does exist.
到處都是鴿子
Full of nuns,
她們溫柔的像天使
so gentle they might be angels.
我希望她們來接我
I wish they'd send for me.
我的上帝
My God.
威廉·拉克漢
William Rackham.
你得對我更好點了
You'll keep me better than you do now.
(切普斯托路)
Chepstow Villas.
等等
Wait, wait!
我的天使
My angel...
終於來了
come at last.
第一集 終
謝謝觀賞